<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.4.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://jakejdavis.me/portfolio/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://jakejdavis.me/portfolio/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-03-26T18:37:41+01:00</updated><id>https://jakejdavis.me/portfolio/</id><title type="html">Jake J Davis</title><subtitle>Hobbyist programmer</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Priory App</title><link href="https://jakejdavis.me/portfolio/Priory-App/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Priory App" /><published>2017-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jakejdavis.me/portfolio/Priory-App</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jakejdavis.me/portfolio/Priory-App/">&lt;p&gt;A webapp which collects infomation from SMHW and E-Praise and shows the data all in one place. Made for Priory School students, created with a Vue.js frontend and PHP backend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you solely want to use the webapp, the production version is found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://jakejdavis.me/priory&quot;&gt;https://jakejdavis.me/priory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hosting&quot;&gt;Hosting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively if you want to host the webapp, you can quickly deploy it to a PHP server where the only prerequisite is curl to make requests to E-Praise and SMHW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;issue-reporting&quot;&gt;Issue Reporting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find any issues with the webapp, please report it! This will increase the chances of it getting fixed sooner. Please follow the issue template when creating an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;built-with&quot;&gt;Built With&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vuejs.org/&quot;&gt;Vue&lt;/a&gt; - The JS framework used&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://materializecss.com/&quot;&gt;Materialize.css&lt;/a&gt; - The CSS framework used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jake Davis&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://jakejdavis.me&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;license&quot;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is licensed under the MIT License&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html">A webapp which collects infomation from SMHW and E-Praise and shows the data all in one place. Made for Priory School students, created with a Vue.js frontend and PHP backend. Getting Started If you solely want to use the webapp, the production version is found at https://jakejdavis.me/priory. Hosting Alternatively if you want to host the webapp, you can quickly deploy it to a PHP server where the only prerequisite is curl to make requests to E-Praise and SMHW. Issue Reporting If you find any issues with the webapp, please report it! This will increase the chances of it getting fixed sooner. Please follow the issue template when creating an issue. Built With Vue - The JS framework used Materialize.css - The CSS framework used Authors Jake Davis - Website License This project is licensed under the MIT License</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Finding &amp;amp; Using Private API’s</title><link href="https://jakejdavis.me/portfolio/Using-Private-APIs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finding &amp; Using Private API's" /><published>2017-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jakejdavis.me/portfolio/Using-Private-APIs</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jakejdavis.me/portfolio/Using-Private-APIs/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;disclaimer&quot;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before following this tutorial I would recommend asking the owner/owners of the APIs if they permit external usage of their APIs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tutorial&quot;&gt;Tutorial&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my Priory App I wanted to intergrate Show My Homework and E-Praise together, unfortunately neither have public APIs avaliable. To find out how SMHW and Epraise works I used an app called &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=app.greyshirts.sslcapture&quot;&gt;Packet Capture&lt;/a&gt; which installs a ssl certificate to your device so it can view network traffic though https as well as http. This app is only avaliable on Android but works on non-rooted devices which is the reason I use this app over others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) So, this app is pretty simple to use, to start logging network traffic just click the play icon in the top right corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/Using-Private-APIs/1.png&quot; height=&quot;500px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Then all you have to do is use the app that you want to log traffic for, some apps may not work like Instagram for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/Using-Private-APIs/2.png&quot; height=&quot;500px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Return back to the app and stop the logging, on this list you can see all the captures that you have ran, click on the most recent (the top one) to view the captures&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/Using-Private-APIs/3.png&quot; height=&quot;500px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) This list shows all the network requests for each app during the time which you were logging, click on one to view the data sent and received&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/Using-Private-APIs/4.png&quot; height=&quot;500px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) This shows the raw data sent between the device and the server, you can see the url and headers but unfortunately the content is unreadable and just a mix of symbols&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/Using-Private-APIs/5.png&quot; height=&quot;500px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) To view this content click on the top right icon labelled “http”, this shows the decoded data and is the reason that the app installs the certificate on the first run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/Using-Private-APIs/6.png&quot; height=&quot;500px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This app was very useful for helping me find out about the SMHW and Epraise APIs for example, what urls I have to request with what headers and what information it will return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Disclaimer Before following this tutorial I would recommend asking the owner/owners of the APIs if they permit external usage of their APIs</summary></entry></feed>